Iram Sharma

114 Sandmere Avenue, Brampton, ON L6Z4A4 Contact no. 647-657-3441 iramsharma17@hotmail.com

Dear Hiring Manager:

This letter is to introduce myself and to let you know of my interest in becoming a part of your company. I feel that the competitive skills attained through my diverse work experiences, trainings and experience make me an excellent fit for this position. In addition to my academic and workplace experience, the professional growth I have attained through my roles and responsibilities has provided insight into working with people in business and technical field.

While my enclosed resume provides a good overview of my strengths and achievements, I have also listed below my applicable skills for some of the specific requirements for this position.

- Master's degree in Environmental Engineering (MEng) from Carleton University, Ottawa (2016- April 2018)
- Bachelor's degree in Chemistry (B.Sc. Hons) from Ryerson University, Toronto. (2011-April 2016)
- Familiar with the GIS software, RS means software, construction cost estimation and MODFLOW
- Solid background in GMP/cGMP practices, Workplace Safety and health policies, ISO compliance and Quality Assurance.
- Access to vehicle for field work

Thank you very much for your consideration. I look forward to hearing from you at your convenience. I may be reached at the cellphone number or email listed above.

Thank you for your time.

Sincerely, Iram Sharma

Enclosure: Resume

▶Iram Sharma

114 Sandmere Avenue, Brampton, ON, L6Z4A4
Contact no. 647-657-3441 iramsharma17@hotmail. com

Key Skills

- Excellent Communication skill in English, both verbal and written
- Hazardous Waste/Solid Waste Management
- Environmental Engineering Unit Operations
- Ground water contaminated site evaluation
- Experience with Arc GIS, MODFLOW and RS means Cost estimation software
- Knowledge of waste water treatment and disposal process

- Experience with MS word, excel in both windows/MAC OS.
- FTIR, HPLC, GC, centrifuge, spectrophotometer, pH meter and conductivity meter
- Team oriented and Collaborative
- Knowledge of Air Pollution intricacies
- Quality Assurance /Regulatory Compliance
- Solid Background in cGMP/GMP practices,
 Workplace Safety and Health Policies

Education

- Secondary School Diploma | North Park Secondary School, Brampton 2008-2011 April
- Bachelor's degree in Chemistry (B.Sc. Hons) | Ryerson University, Toronto 2011-2016 April
- Master's degree in Environmental engineering (MEng)| Carleton University, Ottawa 2016- 2018 April

Work Experience

March'18 to May'18 with 'Medmira Medical Laboratories', Halifax as Quality Assurance Technologist

- Inspected Manufactured sites and performed detailed environmental Monitoring according to Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)
- Take daily environmental readings and perform weekly maintenance on water system. Collecting water samples daily in order to find the TOC, conductivity and HPC count.
- Collecting random samples from the manufacturing area and conducting appropriate tests to make sure the final product is of high quality.
- Maintained control of quality records and material stored in Quality Control quarantine area.
- Monitored clean room operations to ensure compliance with FDA and GMP requirements.
- Monitored product packaging, coordinated inspections for offsite locations.
- Identified labeled and controlled nonconforming product during manufacturing processes.
- Communicated to peers and manufacturing and maintenance personnel, and management the occurrence of in-process product nonconformity.
- Follow SOP's at all times to ensure that both quality and other standard are all met accordingly

Sep'15 to Aug'16 with 'Give & Go', Etobicoke as Production Clerk

- Compile and records production data such as documents, individual worker production sheets.
- Organize files, makes copies, direct phone calls, type up documents, process mail and retrieve records.
- Responsible for signing in and signing out the employees.
- Sending confirmations and requisitions to the agencies.
- Train other staff members to perform work activities such as using computer applications
- Discuss the production reports with production supervisor and the plant manager,

April 2014 to Aug 2014 with Molinaro Italian Food, Mississauga as Quality Control Technician (Co-op)

- Perform pre-operational checks, label checks, net weight checks, package integrity checks, and sensory analysis throughout
 the production.
- Conducted routine and spot inspections of materials, machinery, and production lines.
- Developed and maintained an organized recordkeeping system and prepared meticulous lab reports
- Trained and developed new technician into high performing team members.
- · Operate and maintain microbiology laboratory equipment, Compile records and interpret experimental or analytical results.
- Tests and hands-on inspections are performed before, during and after production to ascertain that products are free from flaws and are of the highest quality.
- Followed all regulations and safety practices at all the time.

April'13 to Jan' 14 with KUMON Tutoring Center, Brampton as Teaching Assistant.

- · Main responsibilities were to do sorting, data entry, marking and teaching higher level math, English and Science to students.
- Raised children's performance and learning levels by continually tracking student progress.
- Observe students' performance, and record relevant data to assess progress,

Supervisor (2011-2014) - SUBWAY Restaurants (Trinity Commons Mall, Brampton)

- Helped company attain the highest customer service ratings (as determined by external auditors) -- earned 100% marks in all
 categories including communication skills, listening skills, problem resolution and politeness.
- Handle customer inquiries, complaints, billing questions and payment extension/service requests.
- Exhibits a cheerful and helpful manner while greeting guests and preparing their orders.
- Uses Point of Sale system/cash register to record the order and compute the amount of the bill.
- Performs paperwork duties and assists with product orders and inventory as needed.
- Received the best employee of the year award for the excelled customer service provided.
- Earned trust of management by opening/closing store and also handling the store keys.

Volunteer Experience

(2014-2015) - Chemistry Laboratory Assistant (Ryerson University, Toronto)

- Conduct Chemical experiments and tests using chromatography, spectroscopy, chemical and physical separation techniques and microscopy
- Prepare solution of gas or liquid reagents and sample formulations
- Keep the record and interpret the results of experiment
- Summarize the research papers
- Responsible for cleaning, calibrating and maintaining the equipment

(2012) - Heart & Stroke Foundation (Canadian National Exhibition, Toronto)

- Pulse rate and E.C.G ambassador
- Communicated and encouraged people regarding health and heart diseases
- Strategy development.
- Carried out Pulse rate and E.C.G check.

Certifications & Trainings

- Workplace Hazardous Materials Information System (WHMIS) Certification
- Standard operating procedure manual & GMP training

Scholarship

- Student Assistantship for Research Project (2016) | Carleton University
- Dean's Honor List of Scholarship (2013) | Ryerson University